Hi, welcome back! In the previous video we looked at how to use the VLOOKUP,
嗨，欢迎回来！ 在之前的视频中，我们 看到了如何使用VLOOKUP函数，
but we didn't yet look at the fourth parameter, as I promised to you.
但我们并没有看到第四个 参数，我许诺过的。
So in this case we only use three parameters -
所以在这种情况下我们只用三个参数 -
what to look, where to find it and what to return.
寻找什么，在哪里可以找到它 并返回。
But, there is still room for a fourth parameter, and maybe,
但是，仍有可能有第四个参数，
if you did the exercises in between, you saw that if you add an additional comma
如果你做了中间的练习， 看到如果你添加一个额外的逗号
then Excel is going to make suggestions for that fourth parameter.
Excel就会给第四个参数提出建议。
Let's have a look at how that looks like. You click,
让我们来看看这是如何运作的。 你点击，
you add a comma, and then Excel says "Hey, I have these two choices for you".
添加一个逗号，Excel会说：“嘿，我这有两种选择。”
Either you use TRUE, which is an approximate match.
你可以选择使用TRUE，这是一个 近似​​匹配。
It's going to give you more or less what you're searching for.
它会或多或少提供给你所查找的东西。
Or, alternatively, we can use FALSE which is going to give you
或者另一选择，我们可以用FALSE。 这是要给你
an exact match, exactly what you're looking for. I would say this is only
精确匹配，准确提供你所查找信息。 我会说这样的描述只
a little bit helpful, so let's try to see the difference
有一点点帮助，所以让我们去看看，
in our example worksheet by putting FALSE into
如果把FALSE放入（其中一列），我们的示例工作表有何差别。
one of the columns. Let's say we put FALSE into the selling price
其中一列（前文已有）。 比方说，我们把FALSE 放入售价一格
and we are going to put TRUE into the lookup
我们打​​算把TRUE放在所查名称位置
of the name. Now we have, side by side, the TRUE and the FALSE version of the
名称（前文已有）。 现在我们有，TRUE和FALSE两个版本并列在
VLOOKUP,
VLOOKUP中，
and that will allow us nicely to see what are the exact
那将使我们清楚准确的看到
differences between the different versions of the fourth parameter.
不同版本中的第四个参数的差异。
So imagine we're in this scenario: one of your colleagues comes into your office
所以，想象我们在这样的场景：你的一个同事进入你的办公室
and he says "Hey, I noticed you've been doing this cool analysis of what turnover we
他说：“嘿，我注意到你一直 在用这炫酷的分析软件
make for what product,
来计算我们各种产品的营业额，
but I would like to know what turnover do we make for
但现在我想了解我最喜欢的产品X098
my favourite product, X098.
的营业额是多少。
Can you calculate that with your spreadsheet?" Of course!
你能用你的电子表格计算出来吗？“ 当然可以！
You can do that with your spreadsheet! So again, we have TRUE in one
你是可以电子表格做到这一点的！ 所以，同样地，我们有一列TRUE和
column and FALSE in the other, and now we're going to input
一列FALSE，现在我们输入X098，
X098, take the formulas that we have,
用上我们已知的公式，
and drag them down. Now you can see what the difference is, because in column C in the
并把它们往下拉。 现在你可以看到有什么 不同的地方，因为在C列的
Selling Price
售价中
we have #N/A, "not found".
我们有＃N / A，“未找到”。
Excel says "Hey, that X098, I can't find it",
Excel中说：“嘿，那X098，我无法找到它”，
whereas, in the B column, Excel can still not find it,
然而，在B列中，Excel还是找不到它，
but he says "Yes, the closest I could find
但他说，“是的，我能找到的最接近
is the Fountain", because alphabetically the H is closest to the X,
是喷泉“，因为按字母顺序H最接近X，
so it just returns whatever value is closest.
所以它只是返回的任何最接近的数值 。
So, I guess from this you can understand what value you usually want.
所以，我想通过这个你能理解你通常想要找到的是什么数值。
You want to use FALSE, because if you have FALSE
我们最好要用上FALSE这个功能，因为
then you get a warning sign if a value that you have searched for
只要用了FALSE，一但你所搜索的内容未能找到
has not been found. So, remember this, if you're using VLOOKUP,
你将会看到警告信号。 所以，请记住这一点，如果 你在使用VLOOKUP
to couple two worksheets together, you're usually
来把两张工作表连在一起
going to want to use FALSE. This is like the basic setting
别忘了使用FALSE。 这就好像基本设置一样
because if you use FALSE you get a warning if
因为如果你使用了FALSE，一旦搜索的内容未被找到，
your result isn't found. Unfortunately,
你会看到警告提醒。 不幸的是，
FALSE is not the default setting. If I remove
FALSE并不是默认设置。 如果我 把这个参数移除
the parameter and restore my formulas as they originally were,
使这些公式 恢复到它们原始的那样，
you see that the behaviour of the formulas is like when I input
你会发现公式的运算方式会变得像输入了TRUE的那样
TRUE - it always tries to find an approximate match.
- 它总会试图找到最接近的​​结果。
This is a bit unfortunate, but yeah, this is the decision that was made by
这是有点遗憾，但没错
the Excel team. Probably didn't really guess that
这是创建Excel的团队的决定结果。 大概他们没有预料到
that connecting a worksheets was going to be the way
人们使用VLOOKUP时
that people use VLOOKUP mostly. So we have to remember ourselves
大多数是连接了多张工作表的。 因此，我们一定要自己记得
to put in FALSE as the
把FALSE设为首选的设置
preferred setting, it is, unfortunately, not the default.
这一点很不幸地并非默认设置。
Don't forget it, because forgetting to add FALSE is one of the reasons of
不要忘记了，因为忘记设置FALSE
many many
是很多
spreadsheet errors.
工作表错误的常见原因之一。